<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sections on Kesugi Ridge Traverse</title>
    <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sections on Kesugi Ridge Traverse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:25:22 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Race Info</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/_race-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/_race-info/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race Rules</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 23:15:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All racers must be signed in at the Little Coal Creek Trailhead by 8:45 a.m.. Race start is at 9 a.m. We will NOT meet on race day at Byers Lake. Carpooling to Little Coal Creek is recommended. Please be aware of State Park parking and camping fees. If you stay at Byers Lake or in the area the night before, you are responsible for your transportation to the start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandatory pre-race meeting 8:45 a.m. Bibs need to be picked up by this time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bibs can not be transferred.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no early race start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No one under 18 at the day of race is allowed to sign up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All racers must check in with officials the morning of the race at Little Coal Creek, even if you picked up your bib the night before at Byers Lake Campground. We need to know who is starting so we can keep track of you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time cut-offs:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full Traverse finish cut-off is 9 hours, or 6 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full Traverse racers must reach the checkpoint just beyond Ermine Hill Trail junction by 1 p.m. (4 hours). Any racer arriving after 1 p.m. will be disqualified and their race bib pulled. Those who do not make the cut-off must take the Ermine Hill Trail down to the road. If someone chooses to go on despite this rule, they may be denied future Kesugi entry. Organizers will ensure a ride back to the finish from the Ermine Hill Trailhead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To receive an official finish, Half Traverse racers must arrive within 4 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are no aid stations. There will be race official at midway and a trail sweep, but no refreshments provided on the course. You are responsible for your own food and water. Drink water along the course at your own risk. There are plenty of available streams, one of which is named Giardia Creek. Friends or family can meet you at Ermine Hill with gear and food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beware of wildlife and please do not wear headphones. Bears have been observed during the race and are common in this area. Moose are also prevalent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandatory gear includes the following: windbreaker, long-sleeved shirt, pants or tights, hat, gloves, sustenance and water bottle. Please don&amp;rsquo;t go &amp;ldquo;Crow Pass style&amp;rdquo; and duct tape everything together around your waist, thereby making it difficult to access. Also bring legitimate gear: no Tyvek painter&amp;rsquo;s suit for your windbreaker and pants layer!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stick to the trail and don&amp;rsquo;t travel overland. Please do not cut the switchbacks. This especially applies to the Cascade Trail that heads down to Byers Lake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not litter! And take care of your trash so it accidentally doesn&amp;rsquo;t become litter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge of the trail is vital. All racers are strongly advised to have traveled the course prior to race day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 23:15:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/requirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Participants for the Full Traverse must have completed at least one of the following trails: Kesugi Ridge Trail, Crow Pass Crossing, Resurrection Pass Trail, Lost Lake, Matanuska Peak Challenge, Granite Tors, Angel Creek 50, Johnson Pass, Juneau&amp;rsquo;s Nifty 50 or some other comparable race or training run.
Participants for the Half Traverse must have completed at least 15 miles of one of the above trails, or 15 miles of some other comparable race or training run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is a question about whether you are qualified, consult with race director Matias Saari.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandatory Gear</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/mandatory-gear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 23:15:25 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/mandatory-gear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Participants for each race must wear or carry the following gear: Windbreaker, long-sleeved shirt, pants or tights, hat, gloves, sustenance and water bottle (or hydration device).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/course/course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:43:15 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/course/course/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mount-sanford&#34;&gt;Mount Sanford&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mount Sanford is a shield volcano in the Wrangell Volcanic Field, in eastern Alaska near the Copper River. It is the third highest volcano in the United States behind Mount Bona and Mount Blackburn. The south face of the volcano, at the head of the Sanford Glacier, rises 8,000 feet (2,400 m) in 1 mile (1,600 m) resulting in one of the steepest gradients in North America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;geology&#34;&gt;Geology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mount Sanford is mainly composed of andesite, and is an ancient peak, being mostly Pleistocene, although some of the upper parts of the mountain may be Holocene. The mountain first began developing 900,000 years ago, when it began growing on top of three smaller shield volcanoes that had coalesced. Two notable events in the mountain&amp;rsquo;s history include a large lava flow which traveled some 11 miles (18 km) to the north east of the peak, and another flow which erupted from a rift zone on the flank of the volcano some 320,000 years ago. The second flow was basaltic in nature and marks the most recent activity of the volcano. The flow was dated using radiometric methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mountain was named in 1885 by Lieutenant Henry T. Allen of the U.S. Army after the Sanford family (Allen was a descendant of Reuben Sanford).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mount Sanford was first climbed on July 21, 1938 by noted mountaineers Terris Moore and Bradford Washburn, via the still standard North Ramp route up the Sheep Glacier. This route &amp;ldquo;offers little technical difficulty&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;is a glacier hike all the way to the summit&amp;rdquo; but is still a serious mountaineering challenge (Alaska Grade 2) due to the altitude and latitude of the peak. The base of the route is usually accessed by air, but landing near the mountain is not straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On March 12, 1948, Northwest Airlines Flight 4422 crashed into Mount Sanford. All 24 passengers and 6 crew members were killed. The wreckage was quickly covered by snow and was not found again until 1999.[5]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first solo ascent of Sanford was achieved on September 19, 1968, by Japanese mountaineer Naomi Uemura, who later died just after making the first solo winter ascent of Denali.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/registration/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 22:49:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/registration/registration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Registration opens April 1, 2017 at &lt;a href=&#34;http://ultrasignup.com&#34;&gt;UltraSignup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/contact/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 23:36:05 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/contact/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/results/results/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 22:49:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/results/results/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>