<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kesugi Ridge Traverse</title>
    <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kesugi Ridge Traverse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:25:22 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Race Info</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/race-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/race-info/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When:&lt;/strong&gt; Saturday June 24, 2017. Race start 9 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where:&lt;/strong&gt; Denali State Park&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Entry Fee:&lt;/strong&gt; $50 on-line. Limited to 100 entrants (50 for each race).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;registration&#34; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Registration:&lt;/strong&gt; begins at 9 a.m. April 1 at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ultrasignup.com/register.aspx?did=47081&#34;&gt;UltraSignup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;contact&#34; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Race director Matias Saari at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:matiasmountain@gmail.com&#34;&gt;matiasmountain@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or cell phone &lt;a href=&#34;tel:907-903-8865&#34;&gt;907-529-4178&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/course/course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:43:15 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/course/course/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Point to point, starting at Little Coal Creek Trailhead and finishing at Byers Lake Campground. The course is approximately 30 miles. Good descriptions can be found in the hiking guides 55Ways to the Wilderness (5th edition) by Helen Nienhueser &amp;amp; John Wolfe Jr. and Hiking Alaska by Dean Littlepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-brief-course-description&#34;&gt;A brief course description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting around 1400 feet, the Full Traverse trail (nearly 30 miles) climbs steadily to above tree line to a high, alpine ridge. The trail is marked with cairns in most places. There will also be flagging and/or pin flags in some key sections. About halfway, the Ermine Hill Trail comes in from the right (elevation 1,500 feet). After the junction, the trail again climbs above tree line until it descends 5 miles to Byers Lake via the Cascade Trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; The suspension bridge one mile from the finish has been removed so participants must wade across Byers Creek. It is only about 25 feet across and the water is slow-moving but potentially thigh- to waist-deep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course will finish in the Byers Lake campground with food, drinks and awards. See pictures below for a couple of good visual directions.
The Half Traverse trail (about 15.5 miles) follows the above route to its finish just uphill from the Ermine Hill Trail junction. Participants will then return 3.5 miles down the Ermine Hill Trail to the Parks Highway at their leisure. A shuttle will then return them to Byers Lake Campground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please be aware.&lt;/strong&gt; This is not a course for beginning trail runners. There are significant climbs, tricky descents and difficult terrain. If you have never traveled the course, we strongly encourage you to do so before signing up. The trail will only have minimal markings, so familiarity with it will be important. Please do not overestimate your abilities! The weather has been inclement in past races, with cold temperatures, rain, snow, wind and low visibility occurring. The time and effort expended at Kesugi is comparable to running up to 2 marathons. If you are a road runner but have never tackled trail running, Kesugi is not for you. Steady running with some power hiking on the hills will be necessary to make the time cut-offs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;visual-directions&#34;&gt;Visual Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have run/hiked the trail before, the trail is fairly easy to follow. It may be problematic if visibility is poor, but if you have familiarity with the course, you should not get lost. Following are a couple of pictures to pay attention to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you pass the Ermine Hill intersection, you will climb up a hill and reach the trail seen below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/img/vis-dir-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Just after Ermine Hill intersection&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will go around the big rock formation (located on your right) and see two open rock &amp;ldquo;doors&amp;rdquo; (picture below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/img/vis-dir-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Go left after passing through the rocks&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go between the doors and head down and to the left. DO NOT take a right at the two large rocks. It is a dead end and will result in up to two hours of wasted time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map &amp; Profile</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/course/map/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:43:15 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/course/map/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/img/kesugi-course-map-2017.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kesugi Ridge Course Map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 23:15:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/requirements/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;qualifying-trail&#34;&gt;Qualifying Trail&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants for the Full Traverse must have completed at least one of the following trails: Kesugi Ridge Trail, Crow Pass Crossing, Resurrection Pass Trail, Lost Lake, Matanuska Peak Challenge, Granite Tors, Angel Creek 50, Johnson Pass, Juneau&amp;rsquo;s Nifty 50 or some other comparable race or training run.
Participants for the Half Traverse must have completed at least 15 miles of one of the above trails, or 15 miles of some other comparable race or training run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is a question about whether you are qualified, consult with race director Matias Saari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;mandatory-gear&#34;&gt;Mandatory Gear&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants for each race must wear or carry the following gear: Windbreaker, long-sleeved shirt, pants or tights, hat, gloves, sustenance and water bottle (or hydration device).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;age-requirement&#34;&gt;Age Requirement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants for each event must be at least 18 years old on race day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;time-cutoffs&#34;&gt;Time Cutoffs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Full Traverse has a time cutoff of 4 hours for the midway point just beyond Ermine Hill Trail junction, and 9 hours for the finish.
The Half Traverse has a time cutoff of 4 hours at the finish line.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race Rules</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 23:15:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All racers must be signed in at the Little Coal Creek Trailhead by &lt;strong&gt;8:45 a.m.&lt;/strong&gt; Race start is at 9 a.m. We will NOT meet on race day at Byers Lake. Carpooling to Little Coal Creek is recommended. Please be aware of State Park parking and camping fees. If you stay at Byers Lake or in the area the night before, you are responsible for your transportation to the start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandatory pre-race meeting &lt;strong&gt;8:45 a.m.&lt;/strong&gt; Bibs need to be picked up by this time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bibs can not be transferred.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no early race start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No one under 18 at the day of race is allowed to sign up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All racers must check in with officials the morning of the race at Little Coal Creek, even if you picked up your bib the night before at Byers Lake Campground. We need to know who is starting so we can keep track of you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time cut-offs:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full Traverse finish cut-off is 9 hours, or 6 p.m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full Traverse racers must reach the checkpoint just beyond Ermine Hill Trail junction by 1 p.m. (4 hours). Any racer arriving after 1 p.m. will be disqualified and their race bib pulled. Those who do not make the cut-off must take the Ermine Hill Trail down to the road. If someone chooses to go on despite this rule, they may be denied future Kesugi entry. Organizers will ensure a ride back to the finish from the Ermine Hill Trailhead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To receive an official finish, Half Traverse racers must arrive within 4 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are no aid stations.&lt;/strong&gt; There will be race official at midway and a trail sweep, but no refreshments provided on the course. You are responsible for your own food and water. Drink water along the course at your own risk. There are plenty of available streams, one of which is named Giardia Creek. Friends or family can meet you at Ermine Hill with gear and food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beware of wildlife and please do not wear headphones. Bears have been observed during the race and are common in this area. Moose are also prevalent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandatory gear includes the following: windbreaker, long-sleeved shirt, pants or tights, hat, gloves, sustenance and water bottle. Please don&amp;rsquo;t go &amp;ldquo;Crow Pass style&amp;rdquo; and duct tape everything together around your waist, thereby making it difficult to access. Also bring legitimate gear: no Tyvek painter&amp;rsquo;s suit for your windbreaker and pants layer!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stick to the trail and don&amp;rsquo;t travel overland. Please do not cut the switchbacks. This especially applies to the Cascade Trail that heads down to Byers Lake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not litter!&lt;/strong&gt; And take care of your trash so it accidentally doesn&amp;rsquo;t become litter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge of the trail is vital. All racers are strongly advised to have traveled the course prior to race day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/contact/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 23:36:05 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/contact/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/registration/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 22:49:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/registration/registration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Registration opens April 1, 2017 at &lt;a href=&#34;http://ultrasignup.com&#34;&gt;UltraSignup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/results/results/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 22:49:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/results/results/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Results can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://ultrasignup.com/results_event.aspx?did=40082&#34;&gt;UltraSignup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Information</title>
      <link>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/other-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:25:22 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kesugiridgetraverse.com/section/race-info/other-info/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are limited options for lodging. Camping at Byers Lake is recommended. Mary&amp;rsquo;s McKinley View Lodge (mile 143.5 Parks Hwy) and Mt. McKinley Princess Lodge are close by. There are also numerous pull-outs where one can camp along the Parks Highway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you plan to leave your car at Little Coal Creek, we suggest not leaving any valuables in your car. Break-ins at State Park parking lots on main roads are common.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>